<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Allen May&#39;s GitHub Page</title>
    <description>Struggling between breadth and depth of knowledge, this site is devoted to  exploring a balance of both deep and wide topics of web development.
</description>
    <link>http://allenmay.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://allenmay.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 07:35:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 07:35:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New DWD Website</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;follow-along-as-we-build-a-new-website-for-the-dayton-web-developers-1&quot;&gt;Follow along as we build a new website for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Dayton-Web-Developers&quot; title=&quot;Dayton Web Developers&quot;&gt;Dayton Web Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share the experience of building our new website were going to talk with group members to get their advice and document what we learn. We’ll also share any challenges we come across and detail about the work put into creating the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: What do we need to know before starting work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Whether your working on your own website, a company web application or a client design the work doesn’t start until their is a “client” need. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; could be the “client”, your boss could be the “client” or your client could be the “client”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll explore that early contact with the client:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2015/06/09/getting-to-know-your-new-client.html&quot; title=&quot;Getting to Know Your Client&quot;&gt;Getting to Know Your Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/the-new-dwd-website.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/the-new-dwd-website.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting to Know You</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;commentor&quot;&gt;For our new website we should ask ourselves the same questions we should ask our clients. Let&#39;s take a closer look at the early discussions with a new client project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;exploring-the-early-relationship-with-a-new-a-client&quot;&gt;Exploring the early relationship with a new a Client&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ClientMeeting.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Client Meeting&quot; class=&quot;postright&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A client is a person looking for your professional advice or service. This person might be from a new business needing a new website or maybe they’re a marketing manager from a large organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they needing your help with a complex project or do they need some consulting advice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our clients are diverse and their needs could be even more diverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So let’s ask some questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
*   What do you think you should know before starting work on a new client project?&lt;br /&gt;
*   What does the client expect from you?&lt;br /&gt;
*   What would you want them to start thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INTERVIEW COMMENTS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;!--
##DRAFT NOTES  - NOT INCLUDED IN ARTICLE


35 questions we will ask new client  
http://www.rogue-element.com/news-blog/35-questions-we-will-ask-new-client

##Let&#39;s connect.  
http://www.rogue-element.com/contact-us/hire-us


So you are interested in working with us? Terrific! We’re flattered. But before we get started, we’ll have some questions to get a feel for your needs and what we can provide. Below is a form to help us all get started. Fill out as little or as much as you like, but this will give us some insight into your needs.

 
WHAT ARE YOU INTERESTED IN?: *
Logo/Identity
Environmental/Signage
Annual Report
Web Design/Strategy
Sustainability Report
Books
Posters/Advertisements
Brochure/Collateral
Other

A FEW QUESTIONS . . .
1) Tell us in a few words about your organization and/or its service or product.

2) What does your organization hope to accomplish with strategic design?
(ie: increased visibility? Sales? Build consumer loyalty? General image upgrade? Other?)

3) Who is your target audience or demographic? Are they already knowledgeable about your organization? What motivates them to use your product/services?

4) What are the key benefits/advantages you offer as opposed to your competitors?

5) What three attributes do you want the audience to think of when they think about your organization?

6) If you require web services, what are your needs?
(ie: Online shopping carts? Video? Migration of lots of files? Calendar modules? Other?)

7) Is there a specific date or series of dates in which you need your project completed?

8) What is your budget?
(Pull the orange slider below to pick a number. We won’t hold you to it, it’s just to give us an idea.)
$0$20,000$40,000$60,000$80,000$100,000+

--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/09/getting-to-know-your-new-client.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/09/getting-to-know-your-new-client.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Real - Enthusiasm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reading “&lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingreal.37signals.com/&quot;&gt;Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/37signals&quot;&gt;@37Signals&lt;/a&gt; and came across content that describes me well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-8---you-cant-fake-enthusiasm&quot;&gt;Chapter 8 - You Can’t Fake Enthusiasm&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go for happy and average over frustrated and great Enthusiasm.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s one attribute you just can’t fake. When it comes time to hire, don’t think you need a guru or a tech-celebrity. Often, they’re just primadonnas anyway. A happy yet average employee is better than a disgruntled expert.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Find someone who’s enthusiastic. Someone you can trust to get things done when left alone. Someone who’s suffered at a bigger, slower company and longs for a new environment. Someone who’s excited to build what you’re building. Someone who hates the same things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of enthusiasm for web development. I spend a lot of my free time “dialed in” to what’s going on in the web development community through meetups, podcast, blogs and tweets. Unfortunately, I’m the only one interested in web development at my 8-5 job so there are rarely opportunities to “talk shop”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pent up enthusiasm sometimes spills out when I go to meetups or have the rare conversation with web-dev peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enthusiasm without being overbearing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I sometimes feel my enthusiasm can be overbearing (or over caffeinated) and I try to keep that “in check”.&lt;br /&gt;
For example, I was recently asked to help co-organize a local meetup. With my typical enthusiasm I said YES!! I’ve offered several suggestions how I could help out and asked if we should meet to do some planning.&lt;br /&gt;
After a couple months and several e-mails I’m not getting much feedback from the current organizer. I &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have put them off by being so overzealous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My personal challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Be enthusiastic, encouraging and supportive without being overbearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide constructive energy without the caffeine =:)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01-07-2015 - Follow up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I received e-mail from the meetup organizer the evening I posted this. They were busy, I was over-anxious to get started. All is good.&lt;br /&gt;
I didn’t “put them off” with my enthusiam, but again I should always keep my enthusiasm from becoming over caffeinated.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:49:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/getting-real-enthusiasm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/getting-real-enthusiasm.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Font Wireup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To add some “flare”, I wired up a “Vollkorn” Google font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done much with web fonts but each time I do it seems to be an easy process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:49:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/simple-font-wireup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/simple-font-wireup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dayton WordPress: Exploring WordPress Workflows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was proud to present at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Dayton-WordPress/events/214530742/&quot;&gt;11/12/2014 WordPress Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
The topic - &lt;em&gt;WordPress Workflows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I planned to be one of several “lightning round” presenters, presenting for 10-15 minutes on a subject. There were no other volunteers to speak, so I was asked to speak the entire hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When giving presentations, I always want to have an interesting message or provide information of value. I had only been to this meetup once before, so I was not sure of the audience. I made some assumptions of what might be a good topic, based on what I would find of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-surprise-guest&quot;&gt;A Surprise Guest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purposely added slides at the beginning of my presentation to promote the other meetups I’m involved with (Clean Coders, GemCityJS, Dayton Web Developers and GiveCamp).&lt;br /&gt;
When I mentioned how GiveCamp is a great resource to plug-into because it’s heavy with WordPress needs, &lt;strong&gt;Rachel Barnett&lt;/strong&gt; (who was sitting on my far left) spoke up and said she can testify to the value of GiveCamp. She came in late so I didn’t see her come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel Barnett is from the Dayton Ombudsman Association - the non-profit project that I was on during GiveCamp 2014. Rachel hung out with our project team at GiveCamp as we worked on their WordPress/database project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During GiveCamp I suggested she come to the WordPress MeetUp to learn more about WordPress. I was pleasantly surprised to see her there and glad she took my advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my presentation we all turned our attention to Rachel’s WordPress needs. We created an impromptu workshop to address some of her problems in WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan Driver (the meeting coordinator) suggested the next meeting be another workshop for Rachel’s WordPress website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something magical about being the pivot point where connections are made, that might not have happened if you were weren’t there.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 13:49:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/12/wordpress-meetup-presentation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/12/wordpress-meetup-presentation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Projects To Consider</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I can’t seem to lock on a project target I’m going to start 
listing random thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post back to this post, with timestamp every time I have an idea for a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2014 - Create an Ember.js / Firebase app at work to do the following:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Verify I can use Firebase throught the firewall&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start using Ember.js more&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add more useable tools to the IntrAnet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2014 - Use the Javascript from a previous project (payment office) do do the following:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create Jasmine testing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use pre-compilers for Javascript and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Document/blog all I learned&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 08:49:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/10/31/some-projects-to-consider.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/10/31/some-projects-to-consider.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Intentions</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-really-mean-to-really&quot;&gt;I Really Mean To… Really!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I’ve got Jekyll figured out. I’m GIT’ing and SASS’ing.. I should be cranking out post after post but reality is [not].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to post something at minimum once a week. Period!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see.. what’s the next topic gonna be.. I know!! Jasmine.
I’ll follow up with some Jasmine walk-through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ooh! then, after that, I can walk through some Firebase stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Allen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 12:49:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/the-best-intentions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/the-best-intentions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open the Window for Some Fresh Air</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;after-a-long-time-trying-i-think-ive-finally-got-my-httpsproxy-settings-set-correctly-i-can-now-use-npm-and-git&quot;&gt;After a long time trying I think I’ve finally got my HTTPS_PROXY settings set correctly. I can now use NPM and GIT!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GIT:&lt;/strong&gt; I have been trying to use GIT inside the corporate firewall for some time. Unfortunately it’s blocked by the proxy server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NPM:&lt;/strong&gt; The same problem affects NODE.JS … I can’t NPM anything because it’s blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has prevented me from doing any modern web development at work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what was the missing piece?..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have the right URL format for my HTTPS_PROXY environment variable. I attempted &lt;code&gt;http://proxyservername:9090&lt;/code&gt; without success. What I was missing was the username/password embedded in the URL:
&lt;code&gt;http://[loginname]:[password]@[proxyserver]:[PORT]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just installed GULP with a &lt;code&gt;$ npm install --global gulp&lt;/code&gt; (I’m soo excited).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With success with NPM I tried GIT. I finally got &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/AllenMay/allenmay.github.io.git&lt;/code&gt; to work for me (YAY! More excitement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to resources that help me find my way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/128035/how-do-i-pull-from-a-git-repository-through-an-http-proxy&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow: How do I pull from a Git repository through an HTTP proxy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7734518/how-to-set-up-git-to-get-through-a-proxy&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow: How to set up Git to get through a proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 12:49:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/18/open-the-window-for-some-fresh-air.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/18/open-the-window-for-some-fresh-air.html</guid>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>nodejs</category>
        
        <category>proxy</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Score: Paper Ball 3 - Jekyll Default 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;mission-create-a-central-profile-blog-using-github-pages&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MISSION:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a Central Profile Blog Using GitHub Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/paperballOPTIMIZED.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Paperball&quot; class=&quot;post-icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great idea - use GitHub Pages as my central blog for projects and interest. Sounds simple enough, right? Well it is simple if you keep focus on the project priority, start with the basics and explore your options later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, after several hours I found myself exploring &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, themes for Jekyll and the GitHub Layout themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is where I went off track:&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted to combine the best parts of all my options and found myself drifting away from the mission.
I had to “paper ball” my efforts 3 times before accepting the fact that I had gone off target and needed to get back to the original goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-ball-1-github-page-layout&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Ball 1:&lt;/strong&gt; GitHub Page Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a GitHub page is an easy implementation, just create a new repo with the name &lt;code&gt;[your GitHubID].github.io&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub provides a nice theme tool to get your GitHub page up and running. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Settings -&amp;gt; GitHub Pages -&amp;gt; Automatic Page Generator&lt;/strong&gt; and you’ll find find several layouts to choose from. I had already installed Jekyll locally and found the default style of Jekyll pretty plain so the MERLOT layout look like a nice style for my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conflict:&lt;/strong&gt; Looking at the MERLOT layout, I didn’t see the same structure as the default Jekyll layout. A lot of the default structure didn’t seem to be in the MERLOT layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to use the MERLOT style on the Jekyll default configuration. &lt;span class=&quot;parened&quot;&gt;(See “Comparison Between MERLOT and Jekyll Default” below)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it turns out the MERLOT Layout is pretty structured and then I would have to redo the mobile style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Paperball!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-ball-2-jekyll-theme-1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Ball 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Jekyll Theme 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah! There are themes for Jekyll! Nice… Let’s go shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first results from searching &lt;code&gt;jekyll themes&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Themes&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a nice looking theme that focused on displaying a portfolio of work for an artist or developer.&lt;br /&gt;
The portfolio grid was nice, and I would use it someday but for now I wanted to just hide it and use a basic blog approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt; The portfolio grid is fed by the _posts listings. So, if I comment-out the portfolio grid, I have no _post ability. Well after a couple hours I realized that I would need to do too much re-engineering to make this work for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Paperball!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-ball-3-jekyll-theme-2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Ball 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Jekyll Theme 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Themes&lt;/a&gt; to see if I can find a tighter fit to a simple blog with some style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found one.. It’s a very nice them and focused on technical blogging. I dive in and start customizing it with my data and find; it’s going to take me another couple hours to get it to a baseline setup before beginning to add any content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be a great solution for a client re-design but not for my immediate need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Paperball!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was running out of project time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I needed to get my blog up and running!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am now back to the basics - the Jekyll default theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You win for now &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll default style&lt;/strong&gt;, but I’m coming back and when I do…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m going to create my own theme!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparison Between MERLOT and Jekyll Default:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;chrome=1&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=640&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:* &lt;code&gt;n/a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
**head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Struggling between breadth and depth of knowledge, this site is devoted to  exploring a balance of both deep and wide topics of web development.
&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;stylesheets/core.css&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;stylesheets/mobile.css&quot; media=&quot;handheld, only screen and (max-device-width:640px)&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;stylesheets/pygment_trac.css&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  `&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/css/main.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;javascripts/modernizr.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.7.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;javascripts/headsmart.min.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                    &lt;code&gt;$(document).ready(function () {&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                    &lt;code&gt;$(&#39;#main_content&#39;).headsmart()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                    &lt;code&gt;})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;n/a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;n/a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/07/paperball-3-jekyll-defaul-1.html&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Allen May&amp;amp;#39;s GitHub Page by AllenMay&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;head.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Score: Paper Ball 3 - Jekyll Default 1&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.MERLOT:&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;default.JEKYLL:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of resources used for this project:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&quot;&gt;Markdown Cheatsheat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 22:41:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/07/paperball-3-jekyll-defaul-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/07/paperball-3-jekyll-defaul-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beginings Can Be Soo Hard!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am building my GitHub pages with Jekyll and exploring the differences between the GitHub site Layout templates.
I’m also exploring the Jekyll themes and trying to incorporate what I like into the right blend of design and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ha! I’ll never get this site up…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finishing this edit and committing to GitHub so I can salvage some of my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow morning becomes for more work on this site….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then… [commit]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 10:11:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/09/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
