<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Allen May</title>
    <description>Struggling between breadth and depth of knowledge, this site is devoted to  exploring a balance of both deep and wide topics of web development.
</description>
    <link>http://allenmay.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://allenmay.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 09:41:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 09:41:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>One A Month</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be more proactive about building my website portfolio using different technologies for each site. If each site uses a different technique then I’ll broaden my experience and keep things from feeling repetitive.&lt;br /&gt;
I decided to give myself a challenge to &lt;strong&gt;complete one website a month&lt;/strong&gt;, every month, through the year 2016. At the end of this challenge I will have 12 examples of websites I’ve created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds easy enough, you can build a WordPress website minutes, but what type of portfolio do I want at the end of this project? I want to stretch myself without being too complicated. Each month project will need to be a balanced so it’s a challenge but can be completed within a month. I will also need to budget my time and pace my work so I’m not tempted to work beyond a month or “double-up” on projects.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/12/29/one-a-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/12/29/one-a-month.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laravel 5 Vendor Libraries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;##Exploring Laravel’s vendor library shows an extensive library that comes with Laravel 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started exploring the world of Laravel and decided to create a reference to all the vendor libraries that come with Laravel 5. I’ve added links to their respective websites for easy access to more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://allenmay.github.io/docs/Laravel%20Vendor%20Libraries.pdf&quot;&gt;Download the Laravel 5 Vendor Libraries PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if I need to make edits to this file.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/11/29/Laravel5_Vendor_Libraries.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/11/29/Laravel5_Vendor_Libraries.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Giving and Receiving</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/giving-receiving-allen-may&quot;&gt;original post 10/24/2015 on LinkedIN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the third year I was part of the 2015 Southwest Ohio GiveCamp in West Chester Ohio. I’m writing this a week after the event and I still reflect on the positive experience I had this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GiveCamp is a weekend event where designers and developers donate their skills to non-profit organizations who need help creating or updating their website, creating a mobile application to increase their outreach or build an application to help track their inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GiveCamp.png&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; title=&quot;Southwest Ohio GiveCamp&quot; /&gt; With previous years I was more distracted with how GiveCamp worked and where I could help out. I was working with complete strangers and we were all unsure of each other’s skills. This year was a better experience because I knew two of my teammates and I was very comfortable with project - building a brand new website with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client - &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicmakersmuseum.com/&quot;&gt;Music Makers Museum&lt;/a&gt; - is a non-profit organization preparing for their grand opening in four months. The museum is a 20 year passion of Rodney and Charlotte Pack. The museum explores the way America has listened and collected music. Their mission is to preserve and share voices and technologies from America’s musical past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-development-team-was-small-but-mighty&quot;&gt;Our development team was small but mighty:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our project leader was Tim Lewis, Software QA Analyst with Everlasting Memories, LLC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Yap, Software Engineer with Hydrotech, Inc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Rizzo, Senior Art Director/Consultant with TiER1 Performance Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Myself Allen May, Web Developer at OmniSpear Web &amp;amp; Network Solutions, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project began on Friday, after the opening ceremonies, forming our teams and gathering in our designated work area. Tim had already met with the client to get some preliminary information and he already setup the web host and domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first task was to get WordPress up and running then walk through the requirements that Charlotte and Rodney had for the website. Charlotte and Rodney brought a USB hard drive full of images, audio files and content to be loaded to the website. Providing 20yrs worth of content made a huge difference on the success of this project. Because it was a brand new website we just need to fill it up with their great content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;providing-20yrs-worth-of-content-made-a-huge-difference-on-the-success-of-this-project&quot;&gt;Providing 20yrs worth of content made a huge difference on the success of this project.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday was a long day of working out everything needed for the website. John did a fantastic job with all those wonderful images they provided. He built a collage of images and “sprinkled” images all over the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy was “heads down”, working out problems with displaying some content in the Exhibits area. He created a clever way to have child content automatically appear in a sub-menu while in the Exhibits section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the WordPress install setup, ironed-out a problem with the website domain and got the audio content to display on the Exhibits section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim helped Jeremy and attended the project leader “stand ups” to report our status. He help make sure we were all on track and headed for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday I provided a 2hr WordPress training for any of the nonprofits that wanted to know how to use WordPress to maintain their website. I found this a very rewarding time because everyone who attended had great questions and we explored several “real world” situations (like installing Google Analytics) for harnessing their WordPress website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the final ceremony and we delivered a beautiful website that Charlotte and Rodney could work with for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was proud to be on this team and I could really connect with Charlotte and Rodney’s vision. They were enthusiastic when they talked about their museum, you could really see Rodney getting excited as he described how he’s building out the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I received a lot from GiveCamp. I made a new friend with John Rizzo (he is an amazing designer), I got to spend time with a former teammate (and MeetUp friend) Jeremy Yap and I got to get to know Tim Lewis and his leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have new friends with Charlotte and Rodney and I feel like I’ve contribute (however small) to the success of their dream of sharing the way America has listened and collected music over the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/10/25/giving-and-receiving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/10/25/giving-and-receiving.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presentation - Dayton Web Developers - Babel and ES6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin-right: 5%; margin-top: -5%;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;/images/DWDSmall.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The August 5th, 2015 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/dayton-web-developers/events/220726745/&quot;&gt;Dayton Web Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; meeting was a bit different from previous meetings. With 28 people attending the audience was larger than normal. Lightning Talks seem to bring people out because they like the variety of topics. Nathan Rambeck was also out of town on vacation so I was in charge of the meeting. 
On top of that, I was one of the 5 presenters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see… pickup the pizza, get the room ready, greet and “warm up” the audience, introduce the topics and speakers, coordinate the “give aways”, AND give a presentation. I was busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully Ricardo Zea and Bryan Braun were there to help. Bryan was also presenting so he was busier than usual also. (big “thank you!” you guys)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-presentation&quot;&gt;My Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My topic, titled “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slides.com/allenmay/deck/fullscreen&quot;&gt;Create a Babel stack to transpile/polyfill ES6 code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;”, was on a skeleton build that uses Babel to transpile ES2015 code into ES5 (older Javascript). 
This was a great topic because &lt;strong&gt;Babel&lt;/strong&gt; allows you to embrace the newer Javascript while using web browsers that don’t support the newer Javascript. I also wanted to let the group know that this small build could be used in a variety of ways- as a test bed, as a new build or a means to get the transpiled Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second time I’ve had a chance to present in front of the Dayton Web Developers group. As an organizer, I feel more compelled to get in front and present to the group. How can I ask them step up while I’m never do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting was a hit! Everyone enjoyed the variety of topics and they seemed to like 5 presenter rather than the 7 we’ve had in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to the next time I can present in front of the group.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/08/05/presentation-dayton-web-developers-babel-and-es6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/08/05/presentation-dayton-web-developers-babel-and-es6.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Testing Babel with IE8</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/babel.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Babel is an ES6 (JavaScript 6) to ES5 (JavaScript 5) transpiler. Transpilers allow you to take advantage of unsupported features now while we wait for new browsers to support these new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still support IE8 at work so I’m looking at Babel as an option to take advantage of ES6 functionality. My ‘babel-starter’ test is taking advantage of ES6’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ecma-international.org/ecma-262/6.0/#sec-arrow-function-definitions&quot;&gt;arrow functions&lt;/a&gt; and, as you’ll see on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://kangax.github.io/compat-table/es6/&quot;&gt;ECMAScript Compatibility grid&lt;/a&gt;, it only starts to have support with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/microsoft-edge&quot;&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will my ‘babel-starter’ run on IE8? I spun up a VirtualBox of Win7/IE8 and was impressed to see ES6 code transpiled and interpreted for use by IE8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Way to go Babel!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s see if we can get &lt;strong&gt;promises&lt;/strong&gt; to work on IE8. Will Bebel help with transpile for IE8? 
There are limits… No, I couldn’t get &lt;strong&gt;promise&lt;/strong&gt; support on IE8 with Babel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the image below, the red line is my &lt;strong&gt;promise&lt;/strong&gt; test and the green line is my &lt;strong&gt;ES6 arrow function&lt;/strong&gt; test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/BabelProofIE8.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/07/31/testing-babel-with-ie8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/07/31/testing-babel-with-ie8.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Babel Starter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning I walked through an insightful video tutorial from &lt;strong&gt;Tuts+&lt;/strong&gt; called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.tutsplus.com/courses/start-coding-es6-with-babel/lessons/babel-on-the-client&quot;&gt;Full Stack ES6 with Babel&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. In this 9 minute video &lt;a href=&quot;http://tutsplus.com/authors/jason-green&quot;&gt;Jason Green&lt;/a&gt; not only demonstrates how to install and configure the &lt;strong&gt;Node.js&lt;/strong&gt; modules he tells you some background on the modules and why you need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 15 minutes of twiddling I had a fully automated &lt;strong&gt;Gulp&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;skeleton&quot; build with &lt;strong&gt;Babel&lt;/strong&gt; integrated to allow me to use &lt;strong&gt;ES6&lt;/strong&gt; code in my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very cool and great foundation. Thanks Jason!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/07/29/babel-starter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/07/29/babel-starter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presentation - Business Intelligence Special Interest Group (SIG)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TechFirstlogo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 6/26/2015 Priyanka Bole (Hobart Service) and I gave a presentation to the &lt;strong&gt;Business Intelligence special interest group&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic of “Presentation / Visualization / Self-Service”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1mn347CMpRPsLrnMjSgGXN5NvMMa23dbnXGZzoSODfik/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Link to Google Presentation in my Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about and presented screenshots of the SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) portal I created for CompuNet that allows managers to create a variety of reports on test turnaround times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priyanka walked through the self-service reporting tool Hobart staff use. She also VPN’ed into their neetwork to give a LIVE demonstration of their reporting toolset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/BI_SIG_Presentation_400x262.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/2015/06/26/presentation-business-intelligence-special-interest-group-sig.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/2015/06/26/presentation-business-intelligence-special-interest-group-sig.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Dayton Web Developers Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;#Follow along as we build a new website for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Dayton-Web-Developers&quot; title=&quot;Dayton Web Developers&quot;&gt;Dayton Web Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share the experience of building our new website were going to talk with group members to get their advice and document what we learn. We’ll also share any challenges we come across and detail about the work put into creating the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: What do we need to know before starting work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Whether your working on your own website, a company web application or a client design the work doesn’t start until their is a “client” need. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; could be the “client”, your boss could be the “client” or your client could be the “client”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll explore that early contact with the client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;post-list&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;li&gt;
        

        &lt;h2&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;post-link&quot; href=&quot;/dwd/getting-to-know-your-new-client.html&quot;&gt;Getting to Know You&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;For our new website we should ask ourselves the same questions we should ask our clients. Let's take a closer look at the early discussions with a new client project.&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    
  &lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/07/the-new-dwd-website.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/06/07/the-new-dwd-website.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Real - Enthusiasm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reading “&lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingreal.37signals.com/&quot;&gt;Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/37signals&quot;&gt;@37Signals&lt;/a&gt; and came across content that describes me well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-8---you-cant-fake-enthusiasm&quot;&gt;Chapter 8 - You Can’t Fake Enthusiasm&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go for happy and average over frustrated and great Enthusiasm.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s one attribute you just can’t fake. When it comes time to hire, don’t think you need a guru or a tech-celebrity. Often, they’re just primadonnas anyway. A happy yet average employee is better than a disgruntled expert.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Find someone who’s enthusiastic. Someone you can trust to get things done when left alone. Someone who’s suffered at a bigger, slower company and longs for a new environment. Someone who’s excited to build what you’re building. Someone who hates the same things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of enthusiasm for web development. I spend a lot of my free time “dialed in” to what’s going on in the web development community through meetups, podcast, blogs and tweets. Unfortunately, I’m the only one interested in web development at my 8-5 job so there are rarely opportunities to “talk shop”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pent up enthusiasm sometimes spills out when I go to meetups or have the rare conversation with web-dev peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enthusiasm without being overbearing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I sometimes feel my enthusiasm can be overbearing (or over caffeinated) and I try to keep that “in check”.&lt;br /&gt;
For example, I was recently asked to help co-organize a local meetup. With my typical enthusiasm I said YES!! I’ve offered several suggestions how I could help out and asked if we should meet to do some planning.&lt;br /&gt;
After a couple months and several e-mails I’m not getting much feedback from the current organizer. I &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have put them off by being so overzealous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My personal challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Be enthusiastic, encouraging and supportive without being overbearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide constructive energy without the caffeine =:)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01-07-2015 - Follow up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I received e-mail from the meetup organizer the evening I posted this. They were busy, I was over-anxious to get started. All is good.&lt;br /&gt;
I didn’t “put them off” with my enthusiam, but again I should always keep my enthusiasm from becoming over caffeinated.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:49:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/getting-real-enthusiasm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/getting-real-enthusiasm.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Font Wireup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To add some “flare”, I wired up a “Vollkorn” Google font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done much with web fonts but each time I do it seems to be an easy process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:49:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/simple-font-wireup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://allenmay.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/simple-font-wireup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
